MARK BLOCKER: In this segment, we're going to cover installing the wheel.
Part of putting the wheel on, I just want to remind you what we're showing you for our video training purposes is on the one side of the car.
The other side of car, you just reverse the application or do everything in reverse orders.
And there are two ways you can do this.
You can do it step by step, as you remove the components on this side, you go to the other side, and remove the components because you have the tools needed right there in your hands and you're really familiar with it.
It's a quick and easy to process that way.
But if you have a problem with laying things out or retention or you're just not that familiar, you might want to do one side at a time; in that way, you can always go over and look at the other side, see how it's put together because it's still unassembled, and it can help you work you through the process to see how everything goes.
It just depends on how comfortable you are with the job, how familiar you are with the components so you can either do it kinda together or you can do it individually, just depends on your comfort level.
I'll just put that information out to you.
We're all ready to go to install the wheel.
I'm just going to put the rotor in straight up and down position so I can readily and easily align the bolts.
Okay, prior to putting on, I always put just a light dosage of anti-seize on the wheels studs and then when I put the nuts on there, as I spin in on down, that's going to spread that anti-seize around and it provides a good lubricant and protection against rust.
So, the next time I have to remove this tire for servicing of any type, I've got a good clean bolts without--that are all rusted up and it just assures a good service life of the bolt and the nut because they are located in an environment where they get a lot of water from rain, from road.
Okay.
Once I get them finger-started, you can just tighten the rest the way down by finger or the star wrench works a little faster.
Now, you want to make sure you hold that rim on there pretty much flat and tied to the rotor, and then dug the nuts down.
Here's a cheating method.
That's a little trick.
It takes a little practice but it breaks up the monotony to do the job and put a little fun into things sometimes.
Okay, we've completed installing the wheel.
Please watch our next segment.
We'll cover installing the lug nuts.